[Music]
hi this is poonam sharma and welcome to
sadhana news
attention go with 19 recover patients
not eligible for insurance for now
the bad news around covet 19 has no end
if you are someone who has recently
recovered from covet 19 and looking to
to buy a life or health insurance policy
you may not get it the life and health
insurers are adopting stringent
underwriting norms for covet 19
recovered patients
in most cases they will have to wait for
up to six months before their proposal
form is accepted
insurance companies are not sure of
long-term effects of covert 19.
different companies are taking different
stance on people who have just turned
covet 19 negative
it depends on underwriting guidelines of
an insurer cesar mitchabara
head health insurance policy.com
health insurance the policy proposer
must be upfront and honest about covet
19 history and submit relevant documents
such as discharge summary if
hospitalized and covered 19 negative
report
even caregivers are supposed to declare
it in the proposal forms
based on your health records the
insurers take a call about accepting
rejecting or postponing the proposal
form medical tests will not be mandated
just on the basis of a covet-19
declaration
a customer is subjected to it depending
on various factors such as age some
insured opted for any pre-existing
conditions at ec
having said that insurers may further
refine the tests that covet recovered
patients may be subjected to
if need be say sanjay datta chief
underwriting
claims and reinsurance icici lombard
general insurance
star health or allied insurance which
has no cool off period for covet 19
says insurance industry needs to be more
inclusive to increase penetration of
health insurance
we have no special criteria to cover co
with 19 recovered patients
we have studied the data we are willing
to cover people who were diagnosed with
covet 19.
they just have to declare it and submit
discharge summary says doctor
s prakash managing director star health
and allied insurance
life insurance life insurers are much
more stringent in underwriting processes
due to life policies being a long-term
contract
they are not even considering the
proposal form before the cool-off period
ends or if they
are they are loading the premium
industry sources and form hdfc life has
a waiting period of 60 days
while at max life it is 90 days for
recovered patients
if they have a history of covert
hospitalization in the last three months
or if they were home quarantined in the
last 30 days
the waiting period is a minimum of three
months says
gupta appointed actuary aegon life
insurance
the uncertainty around covet 19 and
developing strains in the rising claims
are making insurers jittery about
onboarding covet 19 patients
although comet 19 does not qualify as a
chronic disease
the degree of scrutiny is greater for
covet 19 recovered patients
sadja praveen chaudhary had life
insurance policy.com emphasizes there is
nothing unusual about introducing cool
off period for core with 19 patients
life insurers always ask you if you have
had a severe disease in the last six
months
powered by arthroscopic a dedicated
center for
arthroscopy and sports injuries